<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News Archives - Maedapi Cftc</title>
	<atom:link href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/category/news/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:05:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Omegle Was Forced to Shut Down by a Lawsuit From a Sexual Abuse Survivor</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse Survivor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=41</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>OMEGLE, THE VIDEO and text chat site that paired strangers together to talk, ultimately shut down as part of a legal mediation with a female user who sued the company, claiming its defective and negligent design enabled her to be sexually abused through the site. Omegle’s chatting service was shut down Wednesday, just a week ... <a title="Omegle Was Forced to Shut Down by a Lawsuit From a Sexual Abuse Survivor" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/" aria-label="More on Omegle Was Forced to Shut Down by a Lawsuit From a Sexual Abuse Survivor">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/">Omegle Was Forced to Shut Down by a Lawsuit From a Sexual Abuse Survivor</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OMEGLE, THE VIDEO and text chat site that paired strangers together to talk, ultimately shut down as part of a legal mediation with a female user who sued the company, claiming its defective and negligent design enabled her to be sexually abused through the site.</p>
<p>Omegle’s chatting service was shut down Wednesday, just a week after it settled a court case with a plaintiff identified as A.M. Her lawsuit, filed in 2021, alleged that she met a man in his thirties on Omegle who forced her to take naked photos and videos over a three-year period. She was just 11 when it began in 2014.</p>
<p>“The permanent shutdown of Omegle was a term negotiated between Omegle and our client in exchange for Omegle getting to avoid the impending jury trial verdict,” Carrie Goldberg, an attorney who represented A.M., tells WIRED. Attorneys for Omegle did not respond to a request for comment on the settlement. Emails to Omegle were not returned.</p>
<p>Omegle, founded in 2009, regained popularity during 2020 as Covid-19 lockdowns kept people at home. That popularity was, at least in part, driven by it becoming a place where lonely people could chat and also a place for sexual exploration. But its very design was different from other social apps: It instantaneously paired strangers on camera.</p>
<p>“Virtually every tool can be used for good or for evil, and that is especially true of communication tools, due to their innate flexibility,” Leif K-Brooks, Omegle’s founder, wrote in a note announcing the site’s end. “The telephone can be used to wish your grandmother ‘happy birthday’, but it can also be used to call in a bomb threat. There can be no honest accounting of Omegle without acknowledging that some people misused it, including to commit unspeakably heinous crimes.” K-Brooks’ note did not mention the settlement in his statement, but blamed the closure of Omegle on unspecified “attacks” against communication services.</p>
<p>There’s a flaw in K-Brooks’ argument: The telephone doesn’t connect children and teens directly to sexual predators with the click of a button. Omegle’s model allowed sexual predators to sign on and click through a roulette of people, continuously jumping from one to another until they were face-to-face with who they were looking for.</p>
<p>FEATURED VIDEO</p>
<p>Harvard Professor Explains Algorithms in 5 Levels of Difficulty</p>
<p>MOST POPULAR<br />
Which Motorola Phone Should You Buy?<br />
GEAR<br />
Which Motorola Phone Should You Buy?<br />
JULIAN CHOKKATTU</p>
<p>Humane’s Ai Pin is a $700 Smartphone Alternative You Wear All Day<br />
BUSINESS<br />
Humane’s Ai Pin is a $700 Smartphone Alternative You Wear All Day<br />
PARESH DAVE</p>
<p>Maybe (HBO) Max Just Isn’t Worth It<br />
CULTURE<br />
Maybe (HBO) Max Just Isn’t Worth It<br />
ANGELA WATERCUTTER</p>
<p>This AI Bot Fills Out Job Applications for You While You Sleep<br />
BUSINESS<br />
This AI Bot Fills Out Job Applications for You While You Sleep<br />
CAITLIN HARRINGTON</p>
<p>Omegle has a long, problematic history of sexual abuse issues. In August, a man was sentenced to 16 years in prison after admitting to chatting with approximately 1,000 minors on Omegle and recording many of them undressing. The recent settlement with A.M. stems from a $22 million lawsuit which claims the man who abused her had saved thousands of sexually exploitative images of children, including some of A.M. In 2022, a CBC reporter spent time on Omegle and found that the majority of the people she matched to chat with appeared to be men who were either naked or off-camera.</p>
<p>In 2022, there were 608,601 reports of child exploitation on Omegle to the nonprofit National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline. Of all the sites the center tracked, only Facebook, Google, Instagram, and WhatsApp ranked higher.</p>
<p>In the US, social platforms are often protected by Section 230, a broad act that shields them from liability for the content their users post. But the judge in A.M.’s case found last July that Omegle’s design was at fault and it was not protected by Section 230: It could have worked to prevent matches between minors and adults before sexual content was even sent, the judge said.</p>
<p>K-Brooks wrote that he took a “good Samaritan” approach “to implement reasonable measures to fight crime and other misuse.” That included “basic safety and anonymity,” as well as “a great deal of moderation behind the scenes” that used both AI and human moderators. “Omegle punched above its weight in content moderation, and I’m proud of what we accomplished,” he wrote.</p>
<p>Omegle ultimately was brought down by a lawsuit from a sexual abuse survivor. But abusive content will still circulate around the web, and it shows how far away a long-term solution is. “We’ve got to ask ourselves some pretty good questions about how we even permitted this for so long,”  said Signy Arnason, associate executive director of the Canadian Centre for Child Protection, a charity focused on reducing sexual abuse and exploitation of children. “If we don’t address things at the regulatory level, we’re just waiting for another site to backfill what Omegle did.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/">Omegle Was Forced to Shut Down by a Lawsuit From a Sexual Abuse Survivor</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/omegle-was-forced-to-shut-down-by-a-lawsuit-from-a-sexual-abuse-survivor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keke Palmer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Actor Keke Palmer has filed and been granted a restraining order against her former partner, Darius Jackson, and is seeking sole physical and legal custody of their 8-month-old son, Leodis. As reported by People, Palmer filed the domestic violence restraining order with the California Superior Court on Thursday, November 9, alleging that on Sunday, November ... <a title="Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/" aria-label="More on Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/">Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor Keke Palmer has filed and been granted a restraining order against her former partner, Darius Jackson, and is seeking sole physical and legal custody of their 8-month-old son, Leodis.</p>
<p>As reported by People, Palmer filed the domestic violence restraining order with the California Superior Court on Thursday, November 9, alleging that on Sunday, November 5, Jackson trespassed into her home without her knowledge or consent. “Darius… threatened me, then physically attacked me — lunging for my neck, striking me, throwing me over the couch, and stealing my phone when I told him I was going to call the police,&#8221; Palmer stated, including what appear to be screenshots of security footage of the incident.</p>
<p>According to Palmer’s filing, the abuse has been going on for two years. In her filing, the actor cited “many instances of physical violence, including striking and grabbing me around the neck, descriptions of Darius destroying my personal property, including diaries and prescription eyeglasses, throwing my belongings into the street, throwing my car keys to prevent me from driving away, hitting me in front of our son, spewing profanities about me to our son, threatening to kill himself with a gun if I left him, harassment, and other physical and emotional abuse.” The filing also noted “home security footage [from] February 13, 2022 when Darius body slammed me onto the stairs by my neck.”</p>
<p>Keke Palmer Leo Jackson and Darius Jackson<br />
Keke Palmer, Leodis “Leo” Jackson, and Darius Jackson in Atlanta, Georgia in April 2023 GETTY IMAGES<br />
WATCH</p>
<p>Watch Every Moment from Glamour&#8217;s 2023 Women of the Year Event</p>
<p>According to the filing, one incident allegedly occurred when Palmer and Jackson were out to eat in April 2022. The filing states that Jackson allegedly accused Palmer of flirting with a woman and the couple left their meal to return to the hotel. “Darius grabbed my prescription eyeglasses away from me, threw them on the ground and stomped on them,&#8221; Palmer stated. “He then opened my bag, threw all of my belongings onto the pavement in the rain, and threw my car keys across the parking lot before he got into his own car and drove off.”</p>
<p>Palmer said in the filing that she experienced emotional abuse as well as physical. “Darius would &#8216;love bomb&#8217; me and make me feel like I was the most important woman in the world, only to get extremely distant and cold over a perceived insult to him,” her filing stated. &#8220;If we were at a party or event, and I spoke with one person too long or looked at someone a ‘certain way,’ he would storm off in a rage — telling me I was a &#8216;sl*t&#8217; and a &#8216;wh*re,&#8217; accusing me of cheating on him, and that I did not love him. Darius had a way of gaslighting me to make me feel like I was doing something wrong even though I wasn’t.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to The Hollywood Reporter, the temporary order and full custody of the couple&#8217;s son Leodis were granted to Palmer on Thursday, which include “no contact and stay away orders” as well as an order “not to abuse.” A fire arms compliance hearing, which THR reports is “in relation to a hand gun owned by Jackson,” has been set for December 5, 2023. Palmer also filed for sole legal and physical custody of Leo, according to documents obtained by Page Six. Palmer stated she would pay “reasonable expenses of pregnancy and birth&#8221; but requested both parties pay their own legal fees.</p>
<p>Palmer and Jackson began dating in 2021 and welcomed their son on February 25, 2023. In an appearance on Palmer&#8217;s podcast Baby, This is Keke Palmer, Jackson said he initially held Palmer to a “perfect standard” when they began dating, calling going public with their relationship “overwhelming” and “intense.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/">Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Modified District Government Services for Veterans Day</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veterans Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>(Washington, DC) – On Friday, November 10, the District Government will observe the Veterans Day holiday. While some services will be affected, many District employees will continue serving to maintain essential District operations. WHAT’S OPEN ON FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 10 Access to Emergency Shelter All low-barrier shelters for individuals experiencing homelessness operate year-round. All low-barrier shelters remain ... <a title="Modified District Government Services for Veterans Day" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/" aria-label="More on Modified District Government Services for Veterans Day">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/">Modified District Government Services for Veterans Day</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Washington, DC) – On Friday, November 10, the District Government will observe the Veterans Day holiday. While some services will be affected, many District employees will continue serving to maintain essential District operations.</p>
<p>WHAT’S OPEN ON FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 10</p>
<p>Access to Emergency Shelter<br />
All low-barrier shelters for individuals experiencing homelessness operate year-round. All low-barrier shelters remain open 24 hours and will remain open all day on Friday, November 10. Individuals and families seeking access to homeless services should call the DC Shelter Hotline at (202) 399-7093 or the Mayor’s Citywide Call Center at 311 at any time of the day or night.</p>
<p>The Downtown Day Services Center (The Center) is providing walk-in services to guests with no appointment required. Center hours of operation are 9 am – 5 pm, Monday through Friday. Entry will be permitted on a first-come, first-served basis. Guests will be provided with a wristband that must be worn while in the Center. Available walk-in services include showers, laundry, medical &amp; mental health treatment, computer access, electronic/mobile device charging, housing case management, employment counseling, harm reduction services, legal counseling and other vital services. Full capacity lunch services will continue Monday through Friday 11 am – 1 pm.</p>
<p>Zoe’s Doors Youth Drop-In Center for residents experiencing homelessness, located at 900 Rhode Island Avenue NE, will be open from 8 am – 7 pm on Friday, November 10.</p>
<p>Modified Service Adjustments</p>
<p>The DC Department of Public Works (DPW) will slide all household trash and recycling collections scheduled for Friday, November 10 to Saturday, November 11. Leaf collection will operate on schedule. Bulk trash removal will be suspended on Friday, November 10 and will resume on Monday, November 13. For households participating in DPW’s curbside composting pilot program, the collection schedule will slide from Friday, November 10 to Saturday, November 11.</p>
<p>The Benning Road Transfer Station is closed for renovations until further notice.</p>
<p>The Fort Totten Transfer Station will be closed to the public on Friday, November 10. All services will resume on Saturday, November 11 for bulk trash and recycling.</p>
<p>Construction:</p>
<p>The District Department of Transportation (DDOT) will suspend construction and work zones for non-emergency work in roadways, alleys, and sidewalks within the District’s right of way. This includes manhole access and construction-related deliveries. Approved construction activities may resume on Saturday, November 11 during permitted work hours.</p>
<p>Lane Restrictions:<br />
DDOT will not run normal reversible lane operations on Friday, November 10, on the following:</p>
<p>Canal Road between Chain Bridge and Foxhall Road NW<br />
Rock Creek Parkway (controlled by the National Park Service)</p>
<p>The DC Department of Buildings (DOB) does not normally permit construction on District Government holidays, and violations could result in a Stop Work Order and fines. No construction will be allowed on Friday, November 10 for the holiday without a companion Afterhours Permit. Without a companion Afterhours Permit, work for which a construction permit is required is illegal and could result in a Stop Work Order and may be subject to a $4,000 fine. Illegal construction reports can be made using the Illegal Construction Inspection Request Form or afterhours by calling 311. DOB offers many online services, tools, and resources, enabling customers to conduct business 24 hours per day, seven days per week.</p>
<p>Parking Enforcement:<br />
All parking enforcement will be suspended on Friday, November 10, except for Streetcar ticketing and towing. Parking enforcement will resume on Saturday, November 11.</p>
<p>The DC Circulator will run regular service on all routes. The DC Streetcar is operating on a normal schedule.</p>
<p>WHAT’S CLOSED ON FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 10</p>
<p>DC Public Schools (DCPS) will be closed on Friday, November 10 and will resume on Monday, November 13.</p>
<p>DC Public Library (DCPL)  will open the Anacostia Library, Benning (Dorothy I. Height) Library, Mt. Pleasant Library, Petworth Library, Southwest, Tenley-Friendship Library, Woodridge Library on Friday, November 10. The neighborhood libraries will be open from 9 am &#8211; 5 pm. The Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Library will be open from 9:30 am &#8211; 5:30 pm. All Library locations will be closed on Saturday, November 11. The Library will also be available online at dclibrary.org. For more information on available Library programs, visit dclibrary.org or download the Library’s app.</p>
<p>Department of Parks and Recreation (DPR) recreation centers, community centers, and indoor aquatic centers will be closed on Friday, November 10. All previously permitted events in these indoor and outdoor spaces will take place as scheduled. DPR facilities will operate on normal Saturday hours on Saturday, November 11.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/">Modified District Government Services for Veterans Day</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/modified-district-government-services-for-veterans-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frank Borman — a former NASA astronaut Col. who commandeered the Apollo 8 to the moon — has died at the age of 95. Borman died on Nov. 7 in Billings, Montana, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson in a statement posted on NASA’s website on Thursday. He described the space travel pioneer as “one of NASA’s ... <a title="Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/" aria-label="More on Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/">Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frank Borman — a former NASA astronaut Col. who commandeered the Apollo 8 to the moon — has died at the age of 95.</p>
<p>Borman died on Nov. 7 in Billings, Montana, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson in a statement posted on NASA’s website on Thursday. He described the space travel pioneer as “one of NASA’s best” and lauded him for his accomplishments.</p>
<p>“Astronaut Frank Borman was a true American hero,” Nelson said. “Among his many accomplishments, he served as the commander of the Apollo 8 mission, humanity’s first mission around the Moon in 1968.”</p>
<p>“His lifelong love for aviation and exploration was only surpassed by his love for his wife Susan,” he added.</p>
<p>Frank Borman photographed in 1965<br />
Frank Borman photographed in 1965. NASA/ULLSTEIN BILD VIA GETTY<br />
Paying Tribute to the Celebrities Who Have Died in 2023<br />
Borman was born in Gary, Ind., and raised in Tucson, Ariz. and developed a love for aviation at the age of 15, according to his biography on NASA&#8217;s official website. He would go on to earn a Bachelor of Science degree from the U.S. Military Academy, West Point, in 1950 and a Master of Science degree in Aeronautical Engineering from the California Institute of Technology in 1957.</p>
<p>He initially began his career as an officer with the U.S. Air Force. There, he applied his skills to various roles including fighter pilot, operational pilot and instructor, experimental test pilot and an assistant professor of Thermodynamics and Fluid Mechanics at West Point. The culmination of his work with the Air Force eventually led to him being tapped by NASA.</p>
<p>James Lovell (left), command module pilot; William Anders, lunar module pilot and Frank Borman, commander, at the Kennedy Space Center on Dec. 18, 1968<br />
James Lovell (left), command module pilot; William Anders, lunar module pilot and Frank Borman, commander, at the Kennedy Space Center on Dec. 18, 1968. AP PHOTO<br />
“His exceptional experience and expertise led him to be chosen by NASA to join the second group of astronauts,” Nelson said in his statement.</p>
<p>Borman worked on the project Gemini 7 in 1965, in which he spent “14 days in low-Earth orbit” and conducted the “first rendezvous in space, coming within a few feet of the Gemini 6 spacecraft,” according to Nelson.</p>
<p>Walter Cunningham, the Last Surviving Apollo 7 Astronaut, Dead at 90: &#8216;True Hero&#8217;<br />
William Anders (left), James Lovell and Frank Borman in Chicago on April 5, 2018<br />
William Anders (left), James Lovell and Frank Borman in Chicago on April 5, 2018. J.B. SPECTOR/MUSEUM OF SCIENCE AND INDUSTRY, CHICAGO/GETTY<br />
Two years later, Borman served as a member of the Apollo 204 Fire Investigation Board and helped investigate the cause of a fire that killed three astronauts aboard an Apollo spacecraft. He eventually became the Apollo Program Resident Manager, headed the team that reengineered the Apollo spacecraft and served as Field Director of NASA&#8217;s Space Station Task Force.</p>
<p>For his feats in NASA, Borman earned a Congressional Space Medal of Honor from the President of the United States. He was also awarded the Harmon International Aviation Trophy, the Robert J. Collier Trophy, the Tony Jannus Award and the National Geographic Society&#8217;s Hubbard Medal. In 1990, he along with two other astronauts on the Apollo 8 mission were inducted into the International Aerospace Hall of Fame. Three years later, he was inducted into the U.S. Astronaut Hall of Fame as well.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/">Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Split Rock Lighthouse hosts annual Edmund Fitzgerald memorial ceremony</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Split Rock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As dusk settles along the North Shore late Friday afternoon, a crowd of several hundred people is expected to gather at Split Rock Lighthouse to mark the 48th anniversary of the wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald. The memorial ceremony and beacon-lighting is held each Nov. 10 to remember the 29 men who died when the ... <a title="Split Rock Lighthouse hosts annual Edmund Fitzgerald memorial ceremony" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/" aria-label="More on Split Rock Lighthouse hosts annual Edmund Fitzgerald memorial ceremony">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/">Split Rock Lighthouse hosts annual Edmund Fitzgerald memorial ceremony</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As dusk settles along the North Shore late Friday afternoon, a crowd of several hundred people is expected to gather at Split Rock Lighthouse to mark the 48th anniversary of the wreck of the Edmund Fitzgerald.</p>
<p>The memorial ceremony and beacon-lighting is held each Nov. 10 to remember the 29 men who died when the Fitzgerald sank in a Lake Superior storm on Nov. 10, 1975.</p>
<p>The ship would have passed several miles offshore from Split Rock after leaving Superior, Wis., on its last voyage.</p>
<p>The loss of the ship and crew was memorialized by singer Gordon Lightfoot — who died earlier this year — in a now-iconic song. Earlier this year, Split Rock honored Lightfoot’s memory by lighting the beacon in his honor.</p>
<p>Friday’s ceremony will begin at the lighthouse at about 4:30 p.m. The name of each member of the Fitzgerald’s crew will be read aloud as a bell rings 29 times.</p>
<p>Lighthouse staff will then ring the bell once more — a 30th time — to remember all lost mariners. Organizers said the ceremony provides “a time to reflect on the memory of all lives lost on the Great Lakes.”</p>
<p>It is a somber event. It’s a memorial service, essentially, and it is very unique in this sense,” said Hayes Scriven, site manager at Split Rock Lighthouse. “Every time I’ve been a part of this it’s been an emotional thing.”</p>
<p>After the ceremony, the Split Rock lighthouse beacon will be lit, and people in attendance will be able to tour the lighthouse until 6 p.m.</p>
<p>PhotosThe Edmund Fitzgerald remembered<br />
Scriven says he’s expecting about 500 people at the ceremony. U.S. Coast Guard members from Duluth will be there to talk about safety on Lake Superior. Organizers say anyone planning to attend should bring a flashlight or headlamp, and dress for the weather.</p>
<p>For people who can’t make it to the ceremony, a livestream is planned on the Split Rock Lighthouse Facebook page and the Minnesota Historical Society YouTube channel.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/">Split Rock Lighthouse hosts annual Edmund Fitzgerald memorial ceremony</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/split-rock-lighthouse-hosts-annual-edmund-fitzgerald-memorial-ceremony/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2024 GRAMMY Nominations: See The Full Nominees List</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2024 GRAMMY]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Recording Academy has officially revealed nominations for the 2024 GRAMMYs, which will take place Sunday, Feb. 4, at Crypto.com Arena in Los Angeles. The 2024 GRAMMYs, officially known as the 66th GRAMMY Awards, will air live (8:00-11:30 PM, LIVE ET/5:00-8:30 PM, LIVE PT) on the CBS Television Network and will stream on Paramount+ (live ... <a title="2024 GRAMMY Nominations: See The Full Nominees List" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/" aria-label="More on 2024 GRAMMY Nominations: See The Full Nominees List">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/">2024 GRAMMY Nominations: See The Full Nominees List</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Recording Academy has officially revealed nominations for the 2024 GRAMMYs, which will take place Sunday, Feb. 4, at Crypto.com Arena in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>The 2024 GRAMMYs, officially known as the 66th GRAMMY Awards, will air live (8:00-11:30 PM, LIVE ET/5:00-8:30 PM, LIVE PT) on the CBS Television Network and will stream on Paramount+ (live and on demand for Paramount+ with SHOWTIME subscribers, or on demand for Paramount+ Essential subscribers the day after the special airs)^.</p>
<p>Three new GRAMMY categories will debut at the 2024 GRAMMYs: Best African Music Performance, Best Alternative Jazz Album and Best Pop Dance Recording.</p>
<p>These history-making category additions are part of a larger set of updates and amendments, which go into effect immediately at the 2024 GRAMMYs, aimed at making the GRAMMY Awards process &#8220;more fair, transparent and accurate&#8221;, according to Recording Academy CEO Harvey Mason jr.</p>
<p>The GRAMMYs voting process begins with members and record companies submitting entries, which are then screened for eligibility and category placement. The Online Entry Process (OEP) Access Period took place from July 17, 2023 – Aug. 31, 2023. First Round Voting occurred from Oct. 11 to Oct. 20, 2023. Lastly, Final Round Voting will span Dec. 14, 2023 to Jan. 4, 2024 — and the winners will be announced during Music&#8217;s Biggest Night on Feb. 4!</p>
<p>The Academy&#8217;s voting members, all involved in the creative and technical processes of recording, then participate in (1) the nominating process that determines the five finalists in each category; and (2) the final voting process which determines the GRAMMY winners.<br />
For more information, view the GRAMMY Awards Journey, an interactive, engaging online resource about the complete GRAMMY Awards process, from Online Entry and Eligibility Screening to Peer Voting and Nominations.</p>
<p>General Field<br />
1. Record Of The Year</p>
<p>Award to the Artist and to the Producer(s), Recording Engineer(s) and/or Mixer(s) and mastering engineer(s), if other than the artist.</p>
<p>Worship<br />
Jon Batiste<br />
Jon Batiste, Jon Bellion, Pete Nappi &amp; Tenroc, producers; Serban Ghenea &amp; Pete Nappi, engineers/mixers; Chris Gehringer, mastering engineer</p>
<p>Not Strong Enough<br />
boygenius<br />
boygenius &amp; Catherine Marks, producers; Owen Lantz, Catherine Marks, Mike Mogis, Bobby Mota, Kaushlesh &#8220;Garry&#8221; Purohit &amp; Sarah Tudzin, engineers/mixers; Pat Sullivan, mastering engineer</p>
<p>Flowers<br />
Miley Cyrus<br />
Kid Harpoon &amp; Tyler Johnson, producers; Michael Pollack, Brian Rajaratnam &amp; Mark &#8220;Spike&#8221; Stent, engineers/mixers; Joe LaPorta, mastering engineer</p>
<p>What Was I Made For? [From The Motion Picture &#8220;Barbie&#8221;]<br />
Billie Eilish<br />
Billie Eilish &amp; FINNEAS, producers; Billie Eilish, Rob Kinelski &amp; FINNEAS, engineers/mixers; Chris Gehringer, mastering engineer</p>
<p>On My Mama<br />
Victoria Monét<br />
Deputy, Dernst Emile II &amp; Jeff Gitelman, producers; Patrizio Pigliapoco &amp; Todd Robinson, engineers/mixers; Colin Leonard, mastering engineer</p>
<p>Vampire<br />
Olivia Rodrigo<br />
Dan Nigro, producer; Serban Ghenea, Michael Harris, Chris Kasych, Daniel Nigro &amp; Dan Viafore, engineers/mixers; Randy Merrill, mastering engineer</p>
<p>Anti-Hero<br />
Taylor Swift<br />
Jack Antonoff &amp; Taylor Swift, producers; Jack Antonoff, Serban Ghenea, Laura Sisk &amp; Lorenzo Wolff, engineers/mixers; Randy Merrill, mastering engineer</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/">2024 GRAMMY Nominations: See The Full Nominees List</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/2024-grammy-nominations-see-the-full-nominees-list/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
