<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Keke Palmer Archives - Maedapi Cftc</title>
	<atom:link href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/tag/keke-palmer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/tag/keke-palmer/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:04:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keke Palmer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Actor Keke Palmer has filed and been granted a restraining order against her former partner, Darius Jackson, and is seeking sole physical and legal custody of their 8-month-old son, Leodis. As reported by People, Palmer filed the domestic violence restraining order with the California Superior Court on Thursday, November 9, alleging that on Sunday, November ... <a title="Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/" aria-label="More on Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/">Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor Keke Palmer has filed and been granted a restraining order against her former partner, Darius Jackson, and is seeking sole physical and legal custody of their 8-month-old son, Leodis.</p>
<p>As reported by People, Palmer filed the domestic violence restraining order with the California Superior Court on Thursday, November 9, alleging that on Sunday, November 5, Jackson trespassed into her home without her knowledge or consent. “Darius… threatened me, then physically attacked me — lunging for my neck, striking me, throwing me over the couch, and stealing my phone when I told him I was going to call the police,&#8221; Palmer stated, including what appear to be screenshots of security footage of the incident.</p>
<p>According to Palmer’s filing, the abuse has been going on for two years. In her filing, the actor cited “many instances of physical violence, including striking and grabbing me around the neck, descriptions of Darius destroying my personal property, including diaries and prescription eyeglasses, throwing my belongings into the street, throwing my car keys to prevent me from driving away, hitting me in front of our son, spewing profanities about me to our son, threatening to kill himself with a gun if I left him, harassment, and other physical and emotional abuse.” The filing also noted “home security footage [from] February 13, 2022 when Darius body slammed me onto the stairs by my neck.”</p>
<p>Keke Palmer Leo Jackson and Darius Jackson<br />
Keke Palmer, Leodis “Leo” Jackson, and Darius Jackson in Atlanta, Georgia in April 2023 GETTY IMAGES<br />
WATCH</p>
<p>Watch Every Moment from Glamour&#8217;s 2023 Women of the Year Event</p>
<p>According to the filing, one incident allegedly occurred when Palmer and Jackson were out to eat in April 2022. The filing states that Jackson allegedly accused Palmer of flirting with a woman and the couple left their meal to return to the hotel. “Darius grabbed my prescription eyeglasses away from me, threw them on the ground and stomped on them,&#8221; Palmer stated. “He then opened my bag, threw all of my belongings onto the pavement in the rain, and threw my car keys across the parking lot before he got into his own car and drove off.”</p>
<p>Palmer said in the filing that she experienced emotional abuse as well as physical. “Darius would &#8216;love bomb&#8217; me and make me feel like I was the most important woman in the world, only to get extremely distant and cold over a perceived insult to him,” her filing stated. &#8220;If we were at a party or event, and I spoke with one person too long or looked at someone a ‘certain way,’ he would storm off in a rage — telling me I was a &#8216;sl*t&#8217; and a &#8216;wh*re,&#8217; accusing me of cheating on him, and that I did not love him. Darius had a way of gaslighting me to make me feel like I was doing something wrong even though I wasn’t.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to The Hollywood Reporter, the temporary order and full custody of the couple&#8217;s son Leodis were granted to Palmer on Thursday, which include “no contact and stay away orders” as well as an order “not to abuse.” A fire arms compliance hearing, which THR reports is “in relation to a hand gun owned by Jackson,” has been set for December 5, 2023. Palmer also filed for sole legal and physical custody of Leo, according to documents obtained by Page Six. Palmer stated she would pay “reasonable expenses of pregnancy and birth&#8221; but requested both parties pay their own legal fees.</p>
<p>Palmer and Jackson began dating in 2021 and welcomed their son on February 25, 2023. In an appearance on Palmer&#8217;s podcast Baby, This is Keke Palmer, Jackson said he initially held Palmer to a “perfect standard” when they began dating, calling going public with their relationship “overwhelming” and “intense.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/">Keke Palmer Granted Domestic Violence Restraining Order Against Ex Darius Jackson</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/keke-palmer-granted-domestic-violence-restraining-order-against-ex-darius-jackson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
