<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NASA Archives - Maedapi Cftc</title>
	<atom:link href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/tag/nasa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/tag/nasa/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:59:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</title>
		<link>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/</link>
					<comments>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin_cftc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//maedapi.cftc.gov/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frank Borman — a former NASA astronaut Col. who commandeered the Apollo 8 to the moon — has died at the age of 95. Borman died on Nov. 7 in Billings, Montana, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson in a statement posted on NASA’s website on Thursday. He described the space travel pioneer as “one of NASA’s ... <a title="Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’" class="read-more" href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/" aria-label="More on Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/">Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frank Borman — a former NASA astronaut Col. who commandeered the Apollo 8 to the moon — has died at the age of 95.</p>
<p>Borman died on Nov. 7 in Billings, Montana, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson in a statement posted on NASA’s website on Thursday. He described the space travel pioneer as “one of NASA’s best” and lauded him for his accomplishments.</p>
<p>“Astronaut Frank Borman was a true American hero,” Nelson said. “Among his many accomplishments, he served as the commander of the Apollo 8 mission, humanity’s first mission around the Moon in 1968.”</p>
<p>“His lifelong love for aviation and exploration was only surpassed by his love for his wife Susan,” he added.</p>
<p>Frank Borman photographed in 1965<br />
Frank Borman photographed in 1965. NASA/ULLSTEIN BILD VIA GETTY<br />
Paying Tribute to the Celebrities Who Have Died in 2023<br />
Borman was born in Gary, Ind., and raised in Tucson, Ariz. and developed a love for aviation at the age of 15, according to his biography on NASA&#8217;s official website. He would go on to earn a Bachelor of Science degree from the U.S. Military Academy, West Point, in 1950 and a Master of Science degree in Aeronautical Engineering from the California Institute of Technology in 1957.</p>
<p>He initially began his career as an officer with the U.S. Air Force. There, he applied his skills to various roles including fighter pilot, operational pilot and instructor, experimental test pilot and an assistant professor of Thermodynamics and Fluid Mechanics at West Point. The culmination of his work with the Air Force eventually led to him being tapped by NASA.</p>
<p>James Lovell (left), command module pilot; William Anders, lunar module pilot and Frank Borman, commander, at the Kennedy Space Center on Dec. 18, 1968<br />
James Lovell (left), command module pilot; William Anders, lunar module pilot and Frank Borman, commander, at the Kennedy Space Center on Dec. 18, 1968. AP PHOTO<br />
“His exceptional experience and expertise led him to be chosen by NASA to join the second group of astronauts,” Nelson said in his statement.</p>
<p>Borman worked on the project Gemini 7 in 1965, in which he spent “14 days in low-Earth orbit” and conducted the “first rendezvous in space, coming within a few feet of the Gemini 6 spacecraft,” according to Nelson.</p>
<p>Walter Cunningham, the Last Surviving Apollo 7 Astronaut, Dead at 90: &#8216;True Hero&#8217;<br />
William Anders (left), James Lovell and Frank Borman in Chicago on April 5, 2018<br />
William Anders (left), James Lovell and Frank Borman in Chicago on April 5, 2018. J.B. SPECTOR/MUSEUM OF SCIENCE AND INDUSTRY, CHICAGO/GETTY<br />
Two years later, Borman served as a member of the Apollo 204 Fire Investigation Board and helped investigate the cause of a fire that killed three astronauts aboard an Apollo spacecraft. He eventually became the Apollo Program Resident Manager, headed the team that reengineered the Apollo spacecraft and served as Field Director of NASA&#8217;s Space Station Task Force.</p>
<p>For his feats in NASA, Borman earned a Congressional Space Medal of Honor from the President of the United States. He was also awarded the Harmon International Aviation Trophy, the Robert J. Collier Trophy, the Tony Jannus Award and the National Geographic Society&#8217;s Hubbard Medal. In 1990, he along with two other astronauts on the Apollo 8 mission were inducted into the International Aerospace Hall of Fame. Three years later, he was inducted into the U.S. Astronaut Hall of Fame as well.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/">Frank Borman, NASA Astronaut Who Led First Orbit of the Moon, Dead at 95: ‘True American Hero’</a> appeared first on <a href="//maedapi.cftc.gov">Maedapi Cftc</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//maedapi.cftc.gov/frank-borman-nasa-astronaut-who-led-first-orbit-of-the-moon-dead-at-95-true-american-hero/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
